Welcome everyone to build.
I'm Amanda Silver and I'm joined with my friend here,
Marco.
Hello, I'm Marco Castle, Anna.
So I've spent more than two decades working at Microsoft
on developer tools and platforms, and I've really never, ever
seen a shift as profound as the one that we're
going through now.
What we're seeing is that software is evolving from people
driven applications to agents that are defined by intent and
they're measured by the outcomes.
And so these agents can reason, they can retrieve context,
they can make decisions, they can take action on a
user's behalf.
And in many ways this is really the automated future
that we've all been working towards for for decades.
But there's a problem.
More than 40% of agentic AI projects are expected to
fail.
And that's not because the models aren't capable, but it's
because the agents lack the context that they need to
be able to succeed.
And so to make it work, developers actually have to
stitch together the fragmented data sources, the custom retrieval systems,
the permissions models, the orchestration logic just to make agents
useful.
And we're all really figuring this out together.
So we're all learning from each other.
We don't necessarily know what the best practices are, but
the result is that the experiences are brittle for the
end user.
And we see agents that hallucinate.
We see systems that miss policy boundaries and they break
when they're deployed into production.
And the challenge isn't giving agents the access to information.
It's giving them a shared understanding of the people and
the data and the policies and the business context that
surround the agents as they're doing their work.
So when a team actually gets this right, when organizations
get this right, everything changes.
The agents stop acting like isolated apps and they start
operating with an understanding of the enterprise around them, the
people, the data, the work flows and the policies.
And the result is that the agents have better accuracy.
They are more reliable actions there.
There's dramatically less engineering that you need to put into
building these agents, and you don't have to recreate the
context for every single agent that you build.
It's really kind of the difference.
The way I think about it is the difference between
welcoming a brand new employee to the team versus somebody
who's actually a seasoned employee on your team.
So the question is, how can you take that knowledge
that a seasoned employee has and infuse every new agent
with that context as they're executing?
So this is how we think about Microsoft IQ.
You can think about IQ as the context layer for
the agentic web.
It brings together 4 different sources of context.
Work IQ for the organizational context.
Fabric IQ for the business knowledge, Foundry IQ for all
of the enterprise knowledge and policies, and Web IQ for
the world's knowledge.
And together, this system really gives agents a shared understanding
of the world of your business, of the work that's
happening on your teams.
And this is what enables the agents to have enough
context to make the right decision, to take the right
actions, and to achieve the outcomes that you are trying
to get them to achieve so that you can trust
them.
So let's jump into a demo really quickly.
I want to show you what it looks like in
practice.
Last week, I sent Marco an e-mail with an idea,
a crazy idea.
It was.
There was no spec, just an e-mail, no design doc.
And so he's going to show you how he went
from that to a working agent.
All right.
Thank you, Amanda.
All right, so here it is, this is the e-mail
that Amanda sent to me.
So we have this onerous refund process and she thought
it might be a good idea to make an agent
to do this stuff with all the different Iqs.
Now I am going to start with work IQ.
So here I am in copilot CLI and it does
have a handy dandy voice mode over here, so I
think it's Control XV.
Amanda Silver sent me an e-mail about this refund agent
idea.
Let's start to make a plan, a little spec for
this thing so we can build this agent.
Go look up that e-mail.
All right, so what's going to happen here in a
moment is that I have work IQ installed into my
copilot CLI and what it's going to do here, it
is going to use work IQ to go find that
e-mail.
So in this case, I am using, or really it's
using Work IQ on my behalf.
I've authorized it on my behalf.
Or you know, it might have a transient error, but
that happens, you know, it's all good.
OK, so anyway.
There we go.
Well, maybe not I I actually had it preloaded in
a tab, so I'm here, but OK, so we're going
to get a transient error.
Suffice it to say that with Work IQ, it can
log in on your behalf.
And in fact, if you use M365 Copilot, that is
also what it's doing.
You'll notice that for those of you who use Copilot
when you use it, there's a little thing at the
top that says Work IQ and it's using work IQ
to look up your e-mail.
Now in any case, with that, we did make a
spec, and so here is the spec that we ended
up with.
And with this spec, we ended up actually building the
agent itself.
And this is the agent.
Now this agent is using, this is the front end,
the fancy front end for the agent.
But if we look at it in Foundry, this is
what this agent actually looks like.
And in this agent, we are using all four of
the Iqs.
And so, Amanda, if you don't mind, maybe you could
tell us a little bit about Web IQ and Foundry.
Sure, sounds good.
OK, so didn't work.
We're going to come back to work IQ.
Maybe Marco can actually go and debug it.
So we make sure that the the work IQ works
for our later demo.
But basically what we want to see now is that,
you know, we can actually have work IQ kind of
work in combination with Web IQ.
And So what I want to kind of talk about
here is really what is Web IQ in a sense,
the agents don't just need to understand your business.
Often times what they need to understand is the real
world in which your business is operating.
I was talking about talking with somebody today who delivers
consumer goods and he really needs to understand the micro
events, the local events that are happening so that he
can actually have micro targeting of his his different, you
know, consumer goods that he's trying to deliver to all
of these different markets.
So that's a great example of where you might use
something like Web IQ.
So Web IQ really connects AI to authoritative real world
information.
It's structured multimodal index across the web, news, images and
video so that agents can be grounded, have their their
responses grounded in fresh, verifiable context.
It's not a traditional search API.
It's that's wrapped in AI.
It's actually a grounding platform that's built specifically for the
needs of modern agentic systems.
So, you know, if you think about building agents at
scale, three things really matter.
First, quality Web IQ delivers structured, citation ready results across
the web, news, images, video, and it helps the agents
generate the answers that users can verify and trust.
Second, speed.
Agent workflows are inherently multi step and so retrieval and
reasoning and planning and action are all they all add
latency.
So with sub 200 millisecond P-95 grounding, Web IQ really
helps keep those workflows responsive even as the agents chain
together multiple operations.
And third thing we have to think about is efficiency.
The context windows are really valuable real estate.
So Web IQ uses the passage level ranking to surface
the highest signal information while filtering out the noise.
That allows you to reduce the token consumption and lowering
the overall costs of the agents that are operating at
scale.
So Web IQ is already being used by many front
by Frontier model providers and a bunch of enterprises and
it's available today for a few Azure customers.
One example is is NASDAQ.
So they have this solution they call Board Vantage.
And NASDAQ really helps boards and executives make decisions in
real time where the accuracy, the timelines and the trust
are really critical.
And so that means that they can bring together the
enterprise information and all of the external signals that they
can get on the web without having to compromise the
security or the data boundaries.
So with Web IQ, NASDAQ can actually ground the AI
in this fresh, authoritative information so that they can make
all of these decisions in real time.
And the result is faster access to the external contact
context, higher quality responses, and a simpler architecture that allows
them to build AI applications.
So Next up is Foundry IQ.
So if web IQ connects agents to the world's knowledge,
Foundry IQ connects them to your knowledge, enterprise knowledge, you
could think about it as all of that, that context
that is scattered throughout your organization and data platforms and
content repositories in business systems in your custom applications.
Now, today, developers have to spend too much time stitching
all of these sources together before an the agent can
actually deliver the value.
But Foundry IQ changes that.
It provides the unified knowledge layer that automatically ingests and
enriches, and it connects the enterprise information and eliminates a
bunch of the retrieval logic and infrastructure that you would
have to build otherwise.
And then at runtime, when the agent is operating, Foundry
IQ intelligently retrieves the right information for you and from
the right sources, giving the agents the context that they
need to answer accurately and enable the agent to act
confidently.
So that means less infrastructure that you have to manage
and more intelligence for the agents that you're building.
So here's the mental model for Foundry IQ.
At the foundation are your knowledge sources, your enterprise data,
your documents, your applications, and the live web.
And above that is the context layer where memory, embeddings,
and the semantic models all turn that information into understanding.
And then at the top are the agents and the
applications that the users interact with.
So the key idea here is delegation.
Every layer does one thing really well, knowledge sources.
They store the information and the agents retrieve it and
reason over it, and they take action.
And as a developer, you don't want to have to
rebuild that machinery inside every single agent.
You might want to define a knowledge base that you
then make available to multiple agents throughout your organization.
So you want to build on top of it so
that you can get to your solution faster.
But great grounding isn't just about the retrieval, it's also
about trust.
So that's why security and governance and policy enforcement are
built directly into the platform, not bolted on afterwards.
And today we're actually introducing a new serverless developer tier
that gives every developer an easy way to get started
building with Foundry IQ and allows them to scale to
production when they're ready.
Now, several organizations are already using Foundry IQ Sitecore, which
is a leader in digital experience and content management.
It's a great example of what this looks like in
practice.
Foundry IQ gives them reusable knowledge bases, agentic retrieval, and
enterprise grade security out-of-the-box.
And Sitecore took those capabilities and then applied them directly
to a real business problem so that they could make
sure that their marketing and their brand knowledge is accessible
to every agent across their organization, every time, with all
the right permissions.
So that's exactly why we built Foundry IQ, so that
developers can plug in their existing work flows and immediately
empower the agents to be more accurate, more grounded, governed,
and ready for production deployment.
So now let's bring it all together.
Marco's going to show you now what happens when you
connect our refund agent to both Web IQ and Foundry
IQ and grounding it in the real world information, the
enterprise knowledge that you have inside your organization and the
governance required for production.
So you'll see the knowledge base come online, the agent
retrieve the context that it needs, and the policies that
will ensure that it operates safely in production.
Over to you, Marco.
Or we'd like to think that that'll happen.
But in the time that you've been talking up there,
I discovered that my network has gone down hard.
So we're going to, we're going to make do with
what we got here and, and hope for the best.
So now we talked about Web IQ.
Now we have, as I said, we grounded this agent
to all four of the Iqs.
Now with Web IQ that allows us to ground to
real time world data.
Now in this case, I'm asking and now this is
our package delivery system and refunds and things like that.
And I am asking you about the Sandy Fire.
The Sandy Fire is right now still burning 400 miles
South of here in Simi Valley.
And so the idea would be by network we're working
that it will very quickly go to Web IQ and
get back this result and ground this agent to the
real time data.
But I'm not going to sit here and wait for
that to come back because that doesn't seem to be
working.
I even tried hotspotting it to my phone, but not
great.
So we're going to make do with what we got.
Now I am also linking this to Foundry IQ.
So you see, I got my my Foundry IQ over
here.
What's that all about?
So here is Foundry IQ with plenty of little errors
on top due to my lack of a network connection.
But what, what is not a problem here is the
fact that I have connected this to a bunch of
different data sources.
And this highlights one of the key aspects of what
these Iqs are all about, and that is reuse.
You know, the fact is, I got, let's see how
many agents have I got in here?
I got 35 agents in here, of which 31 are
currently running.
And I'm connecting a bunch of them to the same
data sources.
I'm grounding them to the same context.
And So what I don't want to do is redefine
this over and over and over again for every single
agent that I build.
And so instead what I can do is use a
Foundry IQ knowledge base.
Now it's a little bit of a misnomer to call
it a knowledge base because that's not really what Foundry
IQ is.
What it really is, is a separate sub agent.
This is doing a gentic retrieval.
And that means that it can try and try again.
It can re rank results before it gives it up
to my downstream agent.
And so it can search through all of these things
and it reduces the amount of challenge that I have.
He's giving me a new network connection over here.
I'll take that in a minute.
Not right now anyway.
All right.
So basically this allows me to reuse this context across
multiple different agents.
And so with that, Amanda, maybe we can talk a
little bit about now.
You see also we're using here Foundry, sorry, Fabric IQ
in the form of the Fabric data agent.
And why don't you tell a little bit about Fabric
IQ?
While I attempt to repair my network.
Go go, Marco.
We're all rooting for you, man.
All right, so Foundry IQ really helps you unlock all
of the information that your organization knows, but Fabric IQ
is what helps them understand what's happening in real time.
It allows the agents to connect to the data that
you have in your organization, the metrics, the semantic models
and reports that describe the current state of the business
so that they can reason with the same context that
people use to make decisions across your team every day.
So there are really three different outcomes that it can
deliver.
A shared understanding of how the business operates, insights that
can turn those those into actions and agents that can
reason over the business context.
Not just the raw data, but what really is it
at the foundation, There's a unified, there's all of your
unified data in one lake.
So no matter where your data is today, even if
it's not in a Microsoft database, you can actually bring
it into one lake and it can kind of reason
over it.
You can have semantic models that are modeling all of
your business metrics.
Now, most of you have probably already defined these in
Power BI and one of the things that's so incredible
about Fabric IQ is that it could just pick up
what you've already defined in Power BI and start enabling
the agents to reason over it.
And then the ontologies, they capture what your business really
means, all of the entities and the relationships and the
rules and the constraints that your your business operates on.
So all three of those layers live in fabric and
they're Co located with the data that they described.
They're not stitched together as you're trying to assemble it.
So let's first talk about 1 Lake.
You can think about it as a single unified data
layer for your organization, and it brings together the analytical
and operational data across the systems and the clouds that
you're working in without having to constantly move it or
duplicate it.
And that really matters because agents are only as good
as the data that they can access.
But with one lake, every team, every application, and every
agent can work from the same source of truth.
And that eliminates all of the silos and all of
the RE authentication and all of the authentication errors that
you have to deal with.
And it allows these AI systems to have consistent, you
know, scalable and cost effective solutions.
Here now on top of 1 Lake are these semantic
models and they are what bridge the gap between the
data and the business meeting.
And they define the metrics and the concepts that the
orgs that that your teams use to run your business.
Now that way when an agent asks what happened, it
gets the same answer that your Power BI solution, your
Power BI dashboards are going to deliver what your analysts
see and ultimately what you report up to your executives
as well.
Now ontologies, this is what gives the live model of
the business.
It's the entities and the relationships and the rules and
the processes for your for your organization.
Now, that means that the agents can actually reason about
the customers and the orders, not just the tables and
the schemas and the rows.
And you can bootstrap an ontology from your existing semantic
models, or you can create one from scratch, obviously.
But this is what gives agents the native understanding of
how your organization operates.
Now, Quanwa Q Cells manages energy for AI data centers,
and they have a problem that is increasingly too dynamic
and complex for humans to really reason about on their
own.
So they've used Fabric IQ to build an operational model
of the data center that's understood by people, applications, but
also by these AI agents.
And that common understanding is what allows the agents to
reason about the business, the recommended actions and continuously optimize
the operations, all while keeping human operators in control.
And it doesn't replace the human judgement, but it allows
the agents to automate given the context of the business.
All right.
How are we doing, Marco?
I think we're going to have to make do.
OK, OK, OK.
We're having.
So what we're going to show you now is how,
how the refund agent can be grounded in the knowledge
from Fabric IQ using the ontology and the semantic models
that we had defined.
So let's see if Marco can show us what we're
talking.
About I'm going to do the best I can.
I don't know man.
He came out, he gave me a new network, and
it still doesn't work.
So I don't know, maybe my computer just doesn't want
to connect today.
Fortunately, I preloaded a lot of this stuff in case
such a thing happened, and it did.
So here we have it.
Now here's the deal.
It brings me back to the old days of like
when the cloud was really flaky and we had to
do demos and like we had to cache every single
web page.
So thank you, Marco.
Could be worse, right?
At least in blue screen.
All right, Anyway, All right, so here's the deal.
We got all this data in our One Lake catalog.
All this like structured data.
And I as a human, this is how I access
the data.
I'll make all these Power BI reports, but what I'm
not going to do, I'm not going to give Power
BI reports to my agents.
That doesn't make any sense.
I don't know why you do that.
So we need something better for our agents.
Now, underneath these Power BI reports is a semantic model.
The semantic model tells the system what the relationships are
between all of the tables, right?
So you got our packages and our drivers and you
see the one to many's.
And that's almost, almost what an agent needs, but but
not quite, because it kind of tells it about what
the relationships are between these tables and stuff, but it
doesn't really tell it what it means like what it
is.
So fortunately now we got this button over here called
Generate ontology.
And if I were to press it, if I were
to press it, I expect that nothing will happen because
I got no network right now.
But I'm going to press it anyway, just just, you
know, for the feeling.
Yeah.
So as I expected, nothing.
Nothing but and under normal circumstances we would see a,
an ontology generator screen over here that would, you know,
get me started in generating this ontology which I did
do.
So here is the ontology over here and I probably
won't be able to show you too much about this.
But what I will say is now if you look
at this, this is 1 portion of my ontology that
I built.
This is the part about the packages and the customers
and things like that.
And in a way, it kind of looks like the
semantic model, but it's not.
It's different because these things in the mythology, these things
are not tables.
These are business entities.
These are things that matter to your business and these
relationships between them, these are not necessarily table relationships.
These are verbs, so a customer can send or receive
a package.
A package can be sent to customer and that's what
forms the relationships in these ontologies.
You can also add to these things, and I'm not
even going to try to show this right now.
You can also add additional metadata, additional semantics to this.
So for example, what is a package to us?
What do we consider to be a package?
What are some synonyms?
The I might call it a box or a case
or a shipment or something like that.
And so if I'm interacting with this data, I might
use any of these words and this ontology helps the
agent convert those words to what is underneath the scenes
a query.
And so the ontology allows me to give these semantics
to my table to tell the agents what that is
all about.
Now you can use an ontology directly as an MCP
server.
So you, when you define an ontology, there is an
MCP server that you can then connect to or anyway
connect your agents to that will allow them to use
that ontology.
You can also do it here in Fabric IQ.
So I'm sorry, in Foundry IQ.
So you can actually connect Foundry IQ to a Fabric
ontology as well.
And that really what it's doing, it's connected to the
MCP server also.
So it's using that ontology as a data source.
Now in this case, I'm going to just for the
sake of just for sillies, I'm going to reload this
page again just to see if it wants to come
back.
Because if you look closely at the way that I
set up this thing, I actually did not connect it
just directly to the ontology.
And the reason is, well, you're not going to be
able to see it because it's not going to want
to come up.
But the reason I so I connected it instead to
a fabric data agent.
So the fabric data agent is a separate agent.
And with the fabric data agent, I can actually connect
to a whole bunch of different data sources.
So this fabric data agent that you totally can't see
is connected to the ontology, but also to a lake
house and to some other sources.
In that fabric data agent, I have lots of context.
So there's the semantics coming from the ontology itself, but
I also have a lot of semantics that I added
about the lake house.
Because the second real purpose of all of these Iqs
is what I call context delegation.
You know, every agent like this is sitting on top
of a model, and every model has a finite context.
There's only so much that you can put in your
agent's head, so to speak.
And so to query any structured data source, like a
lake house requires tons and tons of context.
You got to give it what is each data source.
You got to give it the data dictionary for each
data source.
You have to give an example queries.
Here's how you query this thing.
And you also have to give it ancillary instructions, like
in my data agent, if only I could show it
to you.
In my data agent, I got a bunch of acronyms,
so I got an acronym in there called SRC, Shipping
Refund Concession, which is specific only to this business.
So it's not going to be in the data, it's
not going to be in the data dictionary.
The models going to have no idea what an SRC
is.
So the only way that it would know what this
term is, is if we tell it, if we define
it.
And this is a lot of what you're doing when
you're developing agents today.
You're inputting this sort of tribal knowledge, this information that
is in your head.
What is an SRC?
Well, now it knows, and so we put all of
that context into the fabric data agent.
So I don't have to put it in here, so
I don't have to define that in every single agent
that I have.
We export that knowledge so that when it needs this
structured data, it doesn't need to keep all that context
in its head.
Instead, it phones a friend.
It calls the fabric data agent to get that data.
Now let's take it away and bring it back to
work.
IQ.
Meanwhile, all right, I'll continue fiddling with the network.
Maybe we'll get it back.
OK, do we have the We have videos.
I don't know.
I don't.
Think we can always bring this up too.
OK, OK.
OK.
So Marco really used work IQ in Act one or
he was supposed to have, if he could have connected
to the network to basically take my e-mail and turn
that into a plan that he then implemented that application
that he showed you a second ago.
Now let's talk about work IQ specifically.
It's really kind of, you could think about it as
the people layer of Microsoft IQ.
What it does is it basically takes all of the
context of what your organization knows.
Now, what does your organization know?
It knows what you guys converse you, you discuss over
e-mail or what you discuss over Teams.
And it basically takes all of that context, all of
the data that lives in M365.
And it allows the agent to be imbued with that
knowledge so that it can understand your business processes, your
collaboration, who is involved in a project, what's important, what
decisions have already been made, what needs the attention next.
Because the most valuable context in an organization isn't just
data, it's actually the people.
It's the people that are collaborating that are working across
the team to get everything over the finish line.
So what makes IQ different than say the graph or
a kind of more any traditional APIs historically?
3 things.
1st, it's built for agents, not users.
If you think about the way that APIs you might
traditional applications might access the graph or an API before
that would be on the scale of a human right?
What is the interactivity that a human needs?
This is really designed to support the speed that an
agentic process would need.
It's also built around the organizational context, not the raw
data.
And it's built on top of your existing security model.
It's not a copy of it.
So all of the work IQ data stays in your
M365 context and in in, you know, that tenant.
And so that means that developers don't have to build
their own systems that index all of this information.
They don't have to extract all of the data from
their M365.
They don't have to build their own retrieval pipelines or
their own governance layer just to help the agents have
the context that all of their other employees have.
It allows the agents to just get the work done,
and work IQ is what provides that foundation out-of-the-box.
Now it's really built for this agent first world.
So traditional APIs, they were built around applications and users.
Work IQ is designed around agents, these systems that need
to reason and retrieve the context and collaborate and take
action across the organization.
And it brings together 4 different capabilities into a single
intelligence layer.
First is chat.
Chat enables the agents to interact with the people and
the other agents, supporting these conversational experiences that you might
get in Microsoft Copilot with the agent to agent collaboration.
Text gives the agents the grounded understanding of what's happening
across the organization, drawing from the emails, the meetings, the
chat, teams, chats, documents, conversations, work flows without having to
require the developers to build their own retrieval orchestration process
or their own index.
The tools provide the capabilities, the simplified and governed way
for agents to retrieve that information, but also to take
action just as any other user would in the context
of M365.
So they can send an e-mail, they can send a
message, and all of that can be used via any
kind of agent friendly service.
And then last I think this is really interesting is
workspaces.
What are workspaces?
They're they're these the persistent place for the agents to
actually work to kind of store their intermediate work product
as they're getting things done.
So if you think about agents are becoming increasingly more
longer running tasks, they need to maintain state.
They need to be able to share their progress across
different phases of the plan that they're executing with other
agents that they might be collaborating with or with humans
that they're collaborating with.
So all of these capabilities together, these, these are what
gives the organizations the same.
I mean, give the agents the same organizational context that
an employee has on your team.
So Miro is a good example of a of a
partner who's been integrating with work IQ and they're basically
integrating all of the context directly into the collaborative experience
for their application as well.
So instead of copying the information between the tools or
working from stale snapshots, the teams can actually access the
same Microsoft 365 context and the documents, the conversations, the
all of the people that they need to collaborate with,
all of those decisions.
But they can now access it directly from the Moreau
canvas.
So there's no copy paste that has to be done.
There's no disconnected tools.
There's no stale information when Moreau is connecting to this
environment.
It's just this shared context that seamlessly flows from M365
into Moreau and vice versa.
Now, that's exactly the kind of connection acted experience that
we all want as end users.
And it's really what agents need to be able to
complete their work without boundaries across all of these different
applications.
So Marco, how?
Oh my gosh.
Oh.
Amanda, I got some good news for you.
Let's do it all right?
Let me tell you the story.
Thank you.
Thank you for bearing with me for the most catastrophic
failure I've ever had on any stage anywhere.
So a gentleman just came up to me from the
audience.
I actually don't know where you came from, but he
came up here and he.
Was from.
Heaven.
Yeah, from heaven, somewhere from Valhalla.
He comes up to me and he goes.
He goes, hey, try turning off global protect.
So I turned off global protect.
It turns out it was globally protecting you all from
seeing my demos.
So I turned it off and we're back online.
I don't know what's up with that, but let's take
a look at this.
So now, now you may remember that back when we
started this thing, you know, we had this kind of
stand alone anonymous agent over here.
But that's how we started.
That's not how we ended up because you see what
we did here, We defined this agent like this.
This agent became a blueprint in a 365 and that
in turn became an agent template.
Now what is an agent template?
Well here let me let me fire this guy up.
Now that I'm back online here, this should go I'm
going to fire this guy up.
But while we're waiting for him, this is my agent
that I made.
Now here's the thing, when you have an agent template,
you can go or any way any user can go
into teams and create an instance of that agent.
So the template by itself is not an agent.
When you instantiate it, that's when you create an agent.
In fact, I didn't just create an agent, I created
my agent.
So if we look at this agent, come on buddy,
wake up.
If we look, here we go again.
If we look at this agent, well, OK, he doesn't
want to open now.
But if we look at this agents in the org
chart, what you're going to find is that this agent
has its own identity and it reports to me.
So OK, doesn't want to click now.
So OK, wants to be challenging still apparently, but it's
not an anyway, maybe this other window will work.
I don't know.
Let's see.
All right, there you go.
Something's happening.
OK, it's it's slow, but it's working.
There you go.
All right, look at that.
There we go.
So this is the refund processor agent itself, and it
is reporting to me.
And I in turn, I'm reporting here to Amanda Silver.
Now, when I create this agent instance, it has its
own Teams box over here.
It also has its own inbox.
Now, I had told it to go check its e-mail.
I told it to check its e-mail.
See, The thing is that I had forwarded it an
e-mail before.
So I forward to my refund processor this e-mail that
I had gotten from Maria Garcia about the fact that
her package hadn't arrived.
So I forwarded that to my agent.
I kind of delegated that work.
And in fact, we can see now that it did
work.
It has emailed back Maria and copied me.
So it emailed Maria and it's like, hey, sorry about
that.
I wasn't able to.
Well, in this case, I wasn't able to find the
package.
So we're full of challenges here today.
But regardless, it was able to send that e-mail directly
back to Maria and copy me.
Now, how did it do that?
How was it able to check its own e-mail box?
Well, it gets us right back to this work IQ.
Work IQ, You could really look at it as the
agent facing headless version of all the Microsoft apps of
Outlook and Teams, of SharePoint and Word.
And this is how my agent is able to interact
with these Microsoft things using its own identity.
And there's an additional advantage to giving this agent its
own identity.
It lives in its own security space.
It has its own rights and permissions.
So earlier, when I checked that e-mail from you, or
when I attempted to check that e-mail from you from
Copilot CLI, I was using Work IQ on my behalf.
So Work IQ in that case was logged in as
me.
But that means that it inherits all of my rights,
all of my permissions.
It can do anything that I can do.
But when I make one of these agent instances, one
of these autopilot agents, then I can give it its
own permission space.
Maybe, I say, you can send and receive emails, but
you can't write Word documents, or you can't change things.
Or maybe you can only draft emails, but it can't
send them.
Whatever that is, I can give it a different set
of security settings to those that I have, thereby limiting
what that agent can do.
But once again, how does it interact with the world
via Work IQ?
Awesome Amanda, we managed to get it back online.
So are we online?
Do you want to just show them like one more
like go back to the fabric?
Yeah, sure.
Kind of.
You know what?
Why do we do?
A little bit more, but.
We do a little quick synopsis of all the things.
So here finally, how is the sense.
So Web IQ, you may remember back in the day,
not that long ago, Web IQ, I asked about the
Sandy Fire and lo and behold, it totally did find
the information about Sandy Fire and how that's affecting us.
It did that here in just a couple of seconds.
So that was cool.
Well, we saw Foundry IQ.
Now, when it came to my fabric data agent, I
mentioned all of that context that I had to give
my fabric data agent.
So I have my different data sources here and I
this was the context I was talking about the description,
the data dictionary, the example queries and these ancillary instructions
over here, including my SRC special acronym.
So this is all the context that you can put
in fabric that you don't have to give to all
your downstream agents.
Say you saw that and you saw a work IQ.
You saw this agent literally reading its e-mail and sending
an e-mail using work IQ.
Awesome.
So yeah, one last one that I I need to
have the satisfaction go back to this to GitHub CLI.
Let's see if we can get work IQ working with
CLI.
Try.
You guys are going to forgive us if it doesn't.
Fit.
Let's see.
Let's see if we can get it to do do
it again now.
So hopefully.
So now we're back to work IQ as me.
Well, that's looking promising here.
And lo and behold, it is indeed asking work IQ.
And in a moment, surely it will find that e-mail
that Amanda sent me.
Awesome.
Great.
OK.
Thank you, Marco.
We, we, we always want to do live demos for
you because we know that you guys like the live
demos as developers, we don't want to give you canned
like, you know, screenshots, all this kind of stuff like
I, I live on live demos.
So that's my my call.
I'm glad we did it and hopefully you guys will
forgive us for it.
But I think what you guys saw is that this
is all agentic delegation that's grounded in the real context.
We had one refund agent that you saw that refund
agent we actually.
Founded it in the web, the real world data we
had the work IQ for all of the people interaction,
all of the historical data of how the teams collaborate.
We had fabric IQ that had all of the business
context around the ontologies and kind of the way the
semantic information of the way that your business actually operates.
And we had Fabric Foundry IQ for all of the
enterprise knowledge that the agent was working on.
And then at the end, you saw how Marco actually
created, he kind of embodied this agent in terms of
giving it an addressable name in the org chart so
that I could send an e-mail to it, I could
interact with it in teams.
This is actually super important because a lot of times,
you know, as developers, we're very used to dealing with
very technical user interfaces, right?
But we're building for people who are used to working
in M365, used to working in teams, interacting in teams.
And so this is a critical, critical capability that allows
a bunch of people who don't necessarily want to go
to a different user interface to be able to interact
with the agent that you're building.
Now, all of this together gives the agents the context
that they need to be able to reason, to decide
to act with confidence.
And you know, in a lot of senses, the future
that we're building together, it's not just filling these agents
with more information that's actually going to make agents very
expensive to operate.
What we need to do is to make sure that
they have the right context so that they can make
the best decision with the most minimum amount of information
that they need with the highest confidence.
So it's really this intelligence that is what makes the
agents useful, and it's the trust that makes them deployable.
So that's why every single layer of Microsoft IQ is
built on the same foundation of identity and governance and
security.
The agents are permission aware by default.
Every action is traceable and explainable, and the policies are
applied consistently across the entire agent ecosystem.
Now, that's because the challenge isn't really just building a
single agent in an intelligent environment.
It's actually building thousands of them.
Actually making sure that your entire organization, as it's building
and deploying these agents, that these are all governed, that
you can trust them.
You can deploy them without having to monitor every single
one of them in a bespoke way.
That you can do it in kind of like a
more unified, unified way so that you can actually make
sure that the agents are behaving the way that you
expect.
So that's really what we've been trying to do across
the board.
And so let's talk about how you guys can all
get started.
Everything that you saw today is available for you to
start building now.
You can try the hands on lab.
We have one that'll be going deep on all of
these Iqs.
You can join us at the booth.
Obviously you can join the discussion on GitHub and you
know, we're really interested in understanding what you guys are
building so that we can really make the the products
better for you.
We really want to see what you're going to be
creating now, if today is keynote, if, if it sparked
an idea for you, this is really where we want
to see you bring it to life.
We have this Agents League hackathon, and that's your chance
to be able to build with everything that you saw
today from, you know, creative applications to autonomous agents to
enterprise grade systems.
Don't just imagine what's possible.
You should actually go and try to build it.
I hope that, you know, today inspired you and, you
know, we're really looking forward to seeing what you're going
to build.
So thank you, everybody, and thank you, Marco, for that.
Yeah.
Thank you all for bearing with us and enjoy the
cold, cold San Francisco summer.
Have a great build.
Thanks everybody.